NICHOLAS SAMEER BARR

CONTACT

Address: Vancouver BC Phone: 778-834-3160

Email: nickbarr100@gmail.com

WWW: https://nickbarr.ca/

EDUCATION

Diploma: Digital Design And Development, 04/2022 **British Columbia Institute of Technology** - Burnaby, BC

1st & 2nd Year : Computer Science, 04/2020 **University of Western Ontario** - London, ON

High School Diploma, 06/2018 High School, Heritage Woods Secondary School - Port Moody, BC

SKILLS

- · Public Speaking
- Strong interpersonal skills
- Effective communicator
- Proven leadership capability

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a BCIT graduate with a solid academic background and leadership roles in sports, I've spent just under two years in the front-end development industry. I'm eager to further explore and seize opportunities in this dynamic field.

WORK HISTORY

Software Developer, 04/2022 to 09/2023 Mellenger Interactive - Vancouver

- Conducted security enhancements and routine maintenance for several WordPress and Drupal Platforms
- Crafted various UI components in React for multiple websites.
- Efficiently resolved hundreds of client website tickets using BugHerd with clarity and precision.
- Discussed issues with team members to provide resolution and apply best practices.
- Participated in software field testing to verify performance of developed projects.

Digital Marketing Manager and Web Developer, 09/2020 to Current **Kinder Kampus Children's Services**

- Redesigned old website to improve responsiveness, accessibility, search optimization by 40% and aesthetics
- Managing digital marketing on Google and Facebook
- Administration support, configuration and commissioning of tablet computers for playing music, video, photos, internet access, and MS word applications at five local childcare centres in Port Moody, BC.

Front End Developer, 09/2021 to 12/2021 BuzzyBee

- Managed full-cycle design tasks, handling phases from conception to completion while maintaining guidelines throughout.
- Completed page components
- Designed fully responsive user interface
- Developed algorithm to receive and restructure data using a custom rest API for the front end

Full Stack Developer, 01/2021 to 05/2021 EcoHow

- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- · Developed page components
- · Designed fully responsive user interface

House Detailing Technician, 04/2020 to 08/2020 **Shack Shine**

- Completed window washing, gutter cleaning and pressure washing of high end residential homes
- Organized and managed equipment, including a Mercedes Sprinter
- Worked with clients to provide exceptional customer service
- Invoiced and completed payments

Customer Service, 05/2017 to 08/2019 **Westwood Plateau Golf And Country Club**

• Welcomed guests, coordinated special events and tournaments, managed golf cart fleet, and assured customer satisfaction at executive golf club in Coquitlam, B.C.

Materials Management, 06/2015 to 08/2017 Creative Children Education Supply

• Managed materials, packaged products, distributed, and fulfilled orders at an educational materials supplier in Port Moody, B.C.